WEI YANG HONG

hongwy@u.nus.edu · LinkedIn · GitHub

Avid software developer/enthusiast familiar with helping create detailed application codes and design. Extensive collaboration with developers/designers from around the world to draft and test programs for in-field rollout. Knowledge-able in version control and popular frontend frameworks necessary for software development.

Experienced in low level languages like C/C++ for performance-based application as well as scripting languages like python for quick prototyping.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN, YIPIT DATA - EDISON SOFTWARE

San Jose, CA | 2021 - Current

Working alongside QA engineers and UI/UX designers headquartered in China and California to develop a frontend iOS/Android webmail via React Native.

- Built upon and debugged native Android java/iOS Swift libraries that are open sourced for certain unique feature requests.
- Developed and debugged UI screens for multiple purposes which were requested by designers and users, and eventually deployed into production once tested by QA.

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN, NUS INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Singapore | 2019 - 2021

Co-developed a wireless sensor prototype via a 3-tier architecture. (Dec 2019 - May 2020)

- Developed the back-end python scripts required for the sensor to automatically capture data and wireless statistics 24/7.
- Developed a user-friendly configurable web dashboard via React library and Node.js backend for the communication between the database and the dashboard

Co-developed an automated solution for IoT devices to be connected to NUS campus network. (Jun 2020 - Jan 2021)

- Developed the HTTP APIs needed for each automated actions and account authentication via Django framework
- Developed and documented the front-end dashboard alongside a UI/UX designer from a wireframe via React library and Material-UI

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING - EXPECTED IN MAY 2022

National University of Singapore | Singapore Computer Engineering Teaching Assistant for CS2113T Software engineering and principles. Current GPA: 4.21/5.0

EXCHANGE- MAY 2021

Stanford University | California Management Science & Engineering Took entrepreneurship courses under NUS Overseas College Scholarship

SKILLS

- Software Development
- Git
- Javascript/React/React Native/NodeJS

- Django/Python
- HTML/CSS
- Java